<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>EduanTech</title>
	<subtitle>A hacker's blog.</subtitle>
	<link href="http://greduan.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self" />
	<link href="http://greduan.github.io" />
	<updated>2013-10-26T01:43:34.052Z</updated>
	<id>http://greduan.github.io</id>
	<author>
		<name>Eduán Lávaque</name>
		<email>eduanlavaque@gmail.com</email>
	</author>

	
		<entry>
			<title>Open Source Games Without Going Poor</title>
			<link href="http://greduan.github.io/posts/open-source-games-without-going-poor.html"/>
			<updated>2013-10-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
			<id>http://greduan.github.io/posts/open-source-games-without-going-poor.html</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR: Release your game for a fee, after a certain amount of time release
source code, continue selling pre-compiled version to public. Open source
games.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what&amp;#8217;s the idea? What do I mean with open source games?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love open source. I try to make everything I use open source whenever
possible. There are lot of great projects I use and sometimes contribute to
that are open source. For example Clojure, Vim, Chromium (all of which I use)
or DocPad (to which I contribute).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also love games, I mean who doesn&amp;#8217;t? Doesn&amp;#8217;t have to be video games for it
to be a game, there&amp;#8217;s also physical games like Tag, Hide-and-Seek etc. They are
all free, open source, they&amp;#8217;re just an idea, you see kids modifying games in
order to make them more interesting all the time! Most video games aren&amp;#8217;t open
source however. You pay for a game, you play it, finish it (or complete it),
move on to the next game. The games that &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; open source are so simple there
isn&amp;#8217;t any gain in making them not open source, if anything you lose from making
them closed source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of, if not all developers love open source. However, a lot of us
developers make games for a living. We can&amp;#8217;t make them open source, we would
have to live off of donations, which are inconsistent if there are donations
and if there aren&amp;#8217;t well&amp;#8230; we&amp;#8217;re in deep shit if we don&amp;#8217;t have a job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, this is an idea I had that tries to solve that. Us open source lovers who
want to make a decent living off of making &lt;em&gt;open source&lt;/em&gt; games will be able to
do this with this idea I had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is simple, release the game to the public for a fee as usual, however
after an agreed amount of time which you decide release the game&amp;#8217;s source. Make
it open source. However, continue selling the pre-compiled game to the public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it&amp;#8217;s really a simple idea. You release the game for a fee for a certain
amount of time in order to make a living or at least make up for what you lost
in the development process. After that certain amount of time is up you release
the source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes the game open source however you are still making an income from
non-techie users or just nice users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why would this work? Smart users would just wait a year or whatever and
compile the source and done, they won&amp;#8217;t pay anything, why would they? They&amp;#8217;re
&lt;em&gt;smart&lt;/em&gt; about it. This idea is just a recipe for disaster!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, the way I see it, if your game is good enough, people won&amp;#8217;t care about
paying for it. They won&amp;#8217;t mind keeping you alive by giving you $5 or whatever
your game costs. In fact they would be glad that you made that game. AND, as an
added bonus, if they&amp;#8217;re interested in the game&amp;#8217;s source code to see how you
figured out this holy-crap-that-looks-crazy thing in your game, they can do
that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most probably if the don&amp;#8217;t pay for your game it&amp;#8217;s because they want some sort
of trial period or they can&amp;#8217;t even afford the game anyway. So really you&amp;#8217;re not
losing much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, there&amp;#8217;ll be the users that just compile the game, play it, finish
and complete it and uninstall it, never touching it again. How many users are
like that? In my experience with people, not many.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this is a trust issue. Do you trust your users enough to be nice enough to
let you live? Or not? I trust them, they&amp;#8217;re playing my awesome game, why
wouldn&amp;#8217;t they want to keep me alive for me to make more games?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can look at it the other way, maybe people are interested in your game not
for the game itself, but the code. They approach your game&amp;#8217;s code because you
figured something out that they&amp;#8217;ve had a hard time figuring out. They figure
out stuff for you that you did wrong and make pull requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you have an income one way or another. Be it through code or money. If they
help with the code they help with the overall game so the sales would be
better, for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just a crazy but not impossible idea I had while thinking on my bed, so
it&amp;#8217;s not really fleshed out, since there isn&amp;#8217;t anything to flesh out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also it&amp;#8217;s kinda hastily written, so if there&amp;#8217;s something you think could be
said better in this post feel free to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Greduan/eduantech.docpad/blob/master/src/render/posts/open-source-games-without-going-poor.html.md&quot;&gt;modify it&lt;/a&gt; and make a pull request
for it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is some further reading you might be interested in:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://raamdev.com/income-ethics-series/&quot;&gt;Income Ethics - Raam Dev&lt;/a&gt; - A very deep look into a similar subject, he
 mentions something extremly similar to this idea in &lt;a href=&quot;http://raamdev.com/income-ethics-series/#public_domain&quot;&gt;this section&lt;/a&gt; of his
 post.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>The Switch to DocPad</title>
			<link href="http://greduan.github.io/posts/the-switch-to-docpad.html"/>
			<updated>2013-06-16T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
			<id>http://greduan.github.io/posts/the-switch-to-docpad.html</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well I finally switched to something else than WordPress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I switched to &lt;a href=&quot;http://docpad.org&quot;&gt;DocPad&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://nodejs.org/&quot;&gt;Node.js&lt;/a&gt; based static website generator.
It&amp;#8217;s a static website generator but if you wish it can be completely dynamic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am using Markdown to write my posts. Using &lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeekup.org/&quot;&gt;CoffeeKup&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sstephenson/eco&quot;&gt;Eco&lt;/a&gt; as
templating languages and &lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeescript.org/&quot;&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/a&gt; for the JavaScript logic. And I am
using &lt;a href=&quot;http://sass-lang.com/&quot;&gt;SCSS&lt;/a&gt; for the CSS, of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, now my website is being hosted by GitHub Pages, so that&amp;#8217;s cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is all. Hope you like the changes. :)&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		</entry>
	
</feed>
