<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>EduanTech</title>
	<subtitle>A web developer and software engineer that loves free software (as in freedom).</subtitle>
	<link href="http://greduan.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self" />
	<link href="http://greduan.github.io" />
	<updated>2014-02-22T20:06:23.858Z</updated>
	<id>http://greduan.github.io</id>
	<author>
		<name>Eduán Lávaque</name>
		<email>eduanlavaque@gmail.com</email>
	</author>

			<entry>
			<title>Real Science, Not Bullshit</title>
			<link href="http://greduan.github.io/posts/real-science-not-bullshit.html"/>
			<updated>2014-02-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
			<id>http://greduan.github.io/posts/real-science-not-bullshit.html</id>
			<content type="html">&#60;p&#62;This one should be short.  But the point is, WTF.  It has always pissed me off
in anime, manga etc., even IRL, that the characters can&#38;#39;t believe what&#38;#39;s
actually happening right in front of them.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;For example.  If in front a scientist a glowing light appeared they would say
it&#38;#39;s not real and it can&#38;#39;t happen, it can&#38;#39;t be happening.  It cannot be
explained thus it has not happened and isn&#38;#39;t happening.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;This defies science itself.  Science is not about &#38;quot;can it be explained?&#38;quot;,
science is about &#38;quot;if we do this 100 times, does it always happen the same way?&#38;quot;.
That&#38;#39;s science and not bullshit.  If it&#38;#39;s happening in front of you, whether or
not you know why, whether you can explain it or not, whether you have any idea
what&#38;#39;s going on or not, it&#38;#39;s happening.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;If something works every time, and it can be constantly proven a certain way,
whether it&#38;#39;s right or not, whether it breaks some &#38;quot;laws of physics&#38;quot; or not, it&#38;#39;s
happening.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I bet if something breaks the speed of light they&#38;#39;ll say that&#38;#39;s impossible
because the speed of light is unattainable except by light.  Even if it&#38;#39;s
happening in front of them.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;BTW, the laws of physics thing, pisses me off how they are called &#38;quot;laws&#38;quot;, but
they are only a set of facts that have been proven to be true most of the time,
not going to say always.  If it suddently turns out gravity repels instead of
attracting, that&#38;#39;s not possible because laws of physics.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;According to the Oxford English dictionary, &#38;quot;is a theoretical principle deduced
from particular facts, applicable to a defined group or class of phenomena, and
expressible by the statement that a particular phenomenon always occurs if
certain conditions be present.&#38;quot;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;So it can be changed, but it seems they are set in stone and will never change
for some reason.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I dunno.  Just pisses me off, that is all.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Share your thoughts with me through email &#60;a href=&#34;&#38;#109;&#38;#x61;&#38;#x69;&#38;#x6c;&#38;#116;&#38;#111;&#38;#58;&#38;#x65;&#38;#100;&#38;#x75;&#38;#x61;&#38;#x6e;&#38;#x6c;&#38;#x61;&#38;#x76;&#38;#97;&#38;#113;&#38;#117;&#38;#x65;&#38;#x40;&#38;#103;&#38;#109;&#38;#x61;&#38;#x69;&#38;#x6c;&#38;#x2e;&#38;#99;&#38;#111;&#38;#x6d;&#34;&#62;&#38;#x65;&#38;#100;&#38;#x75;&#38;#x61;&#38;#x6e;&#38;#x6c;&#38;#x61;&#38;#x76;&#38;#97;&#38;#113;&#38;#117;&#38;#x65;&#38;#x40;&#38;#103;&#38;#109;&#38;#x61;&#38;#x69;&#38;#x6c;&#38;#x2e;&#38;#99;&#38;#111;&#38;#x6d;&#60;/a&#62;.&#60;/p&#62;
<hr/><p>The post <a href="http://greduan.github.io/posts/real-science-not-bullshit.html">Real Science, Not Bullshit</a> appeard first on <a href="http://greduan.github.io">EduanTech</a>.</p></content>
		</entry>
			<entry>
			<title>My Explanation of The Zone</title>
			<link href="http://greduan.github.io/posts/my-explanation-of-the-zone.html"/>
			<updated>2014-02-19T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
			<id>http://greduan.github.io/posts/my-explanation-of-the-zone.html</id>
			<content type="html">&#60;p&#62;So.  A lot of programmers talk about &#38;quot;the zone&#38;quot;, this high performance mode that
programmers get into is one that the most pro of the athletes also seem to
experience.  It is described as a &#38;quot;zone&#38;quot; where the people that experience it are
just so concentrated that nothing distracts them and they can get great work
done very quickly.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Most scientists can&#38;#39;t explain this and the best explanation I have seen of this
(IIRC) is that it&#38;#39;s a result of &#38;quot;time slowing down&#38;quot;, where your senses just get
so sharp you can feel time slowing down, or so it is described.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;You may notice I am mixing two kinds of &#38;quot;zones&#38;quot; here, the programmer&#38;#39;s zone and
the athlete&#38;#39;s zone, this is on purpose, you&#38;#39;ll see later on why. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;h2 id=&#34;hammock-driven-development&#34;&#62;Hammock Driven Development&#60;/h2&#62;
&#60;p&#62;So, I got thinking about this originally because of &#60;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/f84n5oFoZBc&#34;&#62;Rich Hickey&#38;#39;s Hammock
Driven Development&#60;/a&#62;.  I got thinking about his
idea.  There is an excellent summary by the website &#60;a href=&#34;http://data-sorcery.org/&#34;&#62;Data Sorcery With
Clojure&#60;/a&#62; which can be found here:
&#60;a href=&#34;http://data-sorcery.org/2010/12/29/hammock-driven-dev/&#34;&#62;http://data-sorcery.org/2010/12/29/hammock-driven-dev/&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Here&#38;#39;s the image:&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;&#60;img src=&#34;http://incanter.org/images/misc/hammock-driven-dev.png&#34; alt=&#34;Hammock Driven Development cheatsheet&#34;&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Now.  I disagree with him partially.  I do not think it works that way, but
that&#38;#39;s certainly seems to be the result.  So it works, but not for the right
reasons, you could say.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;So Rich is right, partially.  Results, OK, reasons, nein (German no).&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;h2 id=&#34;my-theory-of-hammock-driven-development&#34;&#62;My theory of Hammock Driven Development&#60;/h2&#62;
&#60;p&#62;So how Rich explains it is that there&#38;#39;s basically two minds.  Evaluation and
Preparation.  Probably don&#38;#39;t go by these names in Rich&#38;#39;s world, but you get the
idea.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Now here&#38;#39;s where I disagree.  There&#38;#39;s only one mind in my book, it just has
different priorities, now let me explain that cause it&#38;#39;s not that simple.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;h2 id=&#34;attention-units&#34;&#62;Attention units&#60;/h2&#62;
&#60;p&#62;For now assume attention units are just some kind of unit of concentration or
something, I&#38;#39;ll explain it soon enough.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;OK, so, here&#38;#39;s my idea of how the mind actually works, in terms of the zone.
One mind, different priorities.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;So let&#38;#39;s say I&#38;#39;m just standing still.  My mind at this point is doing all kinds
of shit.  Keeping track of bodily functions, breathing, blood pumping, all of
the organs that process food and stuff, recording perceptions and evaluating
them, keeping balance of the body.  All of this shit is happening real time,
often so quickly and so easily we don&#38;#39;t pay much attention to it, but it&#38;#39;s still
happening.  It is still doing all of that stuff.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Now, consider when you are sleeping or just relaxing.  A &#60;em&#62;lot&#60;/em&#62; of these senses
are dulled or just completely shut down. When I&#38;#39;m sleeping all that&#38;#39;s happening
is breathing, blood pumping, and some bodily functions, but in general my body
is quiet. My senses are practically hibernating (in computer terms), just
awaiting the call that is &#38;quot;I&#38;#39;ve slept enough&#38;quot; or some kind of waking up call, of
any kind.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Now, consider the mind&#38;#39;s availability in both of these situations. In the first
it&#38;#39;s busy, in the second it&#38;#39;s got free time.  People often consider dreams as
just your mind processing and organizing the stuff that happened during the day,
that might very well be it entertaining itself, but that&#38;#39;s another topic.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;OK so now, what are attention units? Let&#38;#39;s say you are... thinking about cats
with your eyes closed while sitting down or laying down.  Most of your attention
units are on the cats, that&#38;#39;s what you&#38;#39;re thinking about, some are on perceptics
etc. There are also some on what you&#38;#39;re going to eat next, mental memos, that
call you need to do right after thinking of cats etc.  Everything you have &#60;em&#62;any&#60;/em&#62;
attention of &#60;em&#62;any&#60;/em&#62; kind has some of your attention units.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Some people have more of these attention units at their disposal, because of
their environment, their natural &#38;quot;talent&#38;quot; (not my favorite word to be honest)
etc.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Now, according to Rich, all the problems we&#38;#39;ve solved have been solved by the
Evaluation mind at some point, and while we consider ourselves smart because we
think of solutions fast it&#38;#39;s just because at some point this problem had already
been solved by the Evaluation mind and you just need to call it back to your
Preparation mind. Rich is actually quite vague IIRC on this, but that&#38;#39;s the
general idea AFAIK.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;So here is my opinion, that&#38;#39;s wrong.  It&#38;#39;s one mind, just different priorities
at different times with different problems and different amounts of attention
units.  Turns out while sleeping it has more time to spend attention units on
your problem, thus solve it.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;People that are good at maths (without being some sort of parrot) just have
attention units at their disposal... and practice.  They have these attention
units in order to have &#38;quot;variables&#38;quot; in their mind of number values that they need
to keep floating around.  Plus good mind processor.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&#62;Summary&#60;/h2&#62;
&#60;ul&#62;
&#60;li&#62;Not two minds, only one.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;Mind has different priorities.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;While sleeping the priorities are few, thus more time for your problems.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;While awake, you can still solve problems from scratch, speed depends from
person to person...&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;/ul&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Of course, this depends &#60;em&#62;greatly&#60;/em&#62; on the person. His emotional and mental status
and aptitude.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;That&#38;#39;s just my two cents, what&#38;#39;s your opinion? Send me an email at
&#60;a href=&#34;&#38;#x6d;&#38;#97;&#38;#x69;&#38;#x6c;&#38;#x74;&#38;#111;&#38;#x3a;&#38;#101;&#38;#x64;&#38;#x75;&#38;#97;&#38;#x6e;&#38;#108;&#38;#x61;&#38;#x76;&#38;#97;&#38;#x71;&#38;#x75;&#38;#x65;&#38;#64;&#38;#103;&#38;#109;&#38;#97;&#38;#105;&#38;#108;&#38;#x2e;&#38;#x63;&#38;#111;&#38;#109;&#34;&#62;&#38;#101;&#38;#x64;&#38;#x75;&#38;#97;&#38;#x6e;&#38;#108;&#38;#x61;&#38;#x76;&#38;#97;&#38;#x71;&#38;#x75;&#38;#x65;&#38;#64;&#38;#103;&#38;#109;&#38;#97;&#38;#105;&#38;#108;&#38;#x2e;&#38;#x63;&#38;#111;&#38;#109;&#60;/a&#62; and tell me all about it. :)&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;&#60;strong&#62;P.S.:&#60;/strong&#62; Forgot to talk about the zone.  Oops.  Basically, just &#60;em&#62;all&#60;/em&#62; of your
attention units are on what matters to you, thus you have more time to think and
nothing distracts you since your attention units aren&#38;#39;t on that.&#60;/p&#62;
<hr/><p>The post <a href="http://greduan.github.io/posts/my-explanation-of-the-zone.html">My Explanation of The Zone</a> appeard first on <a href="http://greduan.github.io">EduanTech</a>.</p></content>
		</entry>
			<entry>
			<title>The World of Window Managers</title>
			<link href="http://greduan.github.io/posts/the-world-of-window-managers.html"/>
			<updated>2014-02-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
			<id>http://greduan.github.io/posts/the-world-of-window-managers.html</id>
			<content type="html">&#60;p&#62;Let me start off by saying that I&#38;#39;m writing this at 23:00 in Switzerland&#38;#39;s time,
so please forgive any stupidities. Usually I go to sleep at 22:00 or something
like that.  Really need to go to sleep for tomorrow...&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Anyway.  I&#38;#39;m going to be talking about WMs (Window Managers) in GNU/Linux, those
that can be found in Arch Linux.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;&#60;strong&#62;TL;DR: I went with &#60;a href=&#34;http://xmonad.org/&#34;&#62;XMonad&#60;/a&#62;, here&#38;#39;s my config files:&#60;/strong&#62; &#60;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Greduan/dotfiles/tree/master/xmonad&#34;&#62;https://github.com/Greduan/dotfiles/tree/master/xmonad&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;So the TL;SR (Too Long; Still Read) version will start by me saying that I tried
almost, if not all of the WMs.  I can confidently say I&#38;#39;m dissapoined there
isn&#38;#39;t a single stacking WM that is keyboard controlled, besides the mouse.
That would be my ideal setup.  But there isn&#38;#39;t, so I tried a lot of dynamic WMs.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;A short list of those I tried is the following:&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;ul&#62;
&#60;li&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;https://github.com/baskerville/bspwm&#34;&#62;BSPWM&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;http://xmonad.org/&#34;&#62;XMonad&#60;/a&#62;, I went with this one&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;https://bbs.archlinux.org/viewtopic.php?id=146889&#34;&#62;Alopex&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;http://awesome.naquadah.org/&#34;&#62;awesome&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;/ul&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Those are the most notable ones.  The ones that I honestly tried for a while and
can give a fair review or opinion for.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;h2 id=&#34;alopex&#34;&#62;Alopex&#60;/h2&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Let&#38;#39;s start with Alopex.  Alopex is the one I like the most after XMonad.  I&#38;#39;ve
used it for at least... 2 or 3 months or something.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;It is very nice, almost ideal, but it lacks the configurability I like.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;h2 id=&#34;awesome&#34;&#62;awesome&#60;/h2&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Another one I really liked.  I used this one for... 1 or 2 weeks, give or take a
few.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I liked it but it&#38;#39;s too heavy for me. Also I don&#38;#39;t like Lua and the config seems
to change every single update, which isn&#38;#39;t good IMO.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;h2 id=&#34;bspwm&#34;&#62;BSPWM&#60;/h2&#62;
&#60;p&#62;This is the one I was most excited for TBH, but I couldn&#38;#39;t get Dzen2 to work
correctly with it so I had to give up. Super powerful window management though,
I suggest you try this one before XMonad.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;h2 id=&#34;xmonad&#34;&#62;XMonad&#60;/h2&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Finally XMonad.  The king of tiling WMs it seems.  Atleast for me.  What makes
XMonad unique for me is that it&#38;#39;s written in &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.haskell.org/haskellwiki/Haskell&#34;&#62;Haskell&#60;/a&#62;,
the language I have my eye on, and that I&#38;#39;m currently trying to learn, to a
degree, to see if I like it.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;A config tutorial, tour whatever will come later in another blog post, in the
meanwhile just know I went with XMonad, and you can find my config files here: &#60;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Greduan/dotfiles/tree/master/xmonad&#34;&#62;https://github.com/Greduan/dotfiles/tree/master/xmonad&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;If there&#38;#39;s something you think could be said better in this post or you find a
typo feel free to &#60;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Greduan/eduantech.docpad/blob/master/src/render/posts/the-world-of-window-managers.html.md&#34;&#62;modify it&#60;/a&#62;
and make a pull request for it!&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Thank you for reading! You can share your thoughts with me through email at
&#60;a href=&#34;&#38;#109;&#38;#97;&#38;#105;&#38;#x6c;&#38;#116;&#38;#111;&#38;#x3a;&#38;#101;&#38;#x64;&#38;#117;&#38;#x61;&#38;#110;&#38;#x6c;&#38;#x61;&#38;#118;&#38;#x61;&#38;#x71;&#38;#x75;&#38;#101;&#38;#x40;&#38;#103;&#38;#109;&#38;#x61;&#38;#105;&#38;#108;&#38;#x2e;&#38;#99;&#38;#111;&#38;#109;&#34;&#62;&#38;#101;&#38;#x64;&#38;#117;&#38;#x61;&#38;#110;&#38;#x6c;&#38;#x61;&#38;#118;&#38;#x61;&#38;#x71;&#38;#x75;&#38;#101;&#38;#x40;&#38;#103;&#38;#109;&#38;#x61;&#38;#105;&#38;#108;&#38;#x2e;&#38;#99;&#38;#111;&#38;#109;&#60;/a&#62;. :)&#60;/p&#62;
<hr/><p>The post <a href="http://greduan.github.io/posts/the-world-of-window-managers.html">The World of Window Managers</a> appeard first on <a href="http://greduan.github.io">EduanTech</a>.</p></content>
		</entry>
			<entry>
			<title>My Trip to Switzerland, Part 1, Getting There</title>
			<link href="http://greduan.github.io/posts/my-trip-to-switzerland-part-1.html"/>
			<updated>2014-01-15T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
			<id>http://greduan.github.io/posts/my-trip-to-switzerland-part-1.html</id>
			<content type="html">&#60;p&#62;I&#38;#39;d like to make it clear that this will probably be writen over several
sessions over several days.  I&#38;#39;ve mentioned several times that I won&#38;#39;t have good
internet during the time I&#38;#39;m over here, so I&#38;#39;m sticking to that.  Sorry if some
info is inconsistent, I&#38;#39;ll do my best to keep it consistent.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Also the time and date formats will be kept as near to the Switzerland method
for written time as possible, since I like it.  I.E. time is in 24 hour format
and dates use &#38;quot;.&#38;quot; in between and it&#38;#39;s a &#60;code&#62;DD.MM.YYYY&#60;/code&#62; format, not the crazy
&#60;code&#62;MM/DD/YYYY&#60;/code&#62; format USA uses.  Swear to god all they need to do is make a USD
worth 99 cents and they will have officially messed up their entire numerical
system.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Also I&#38;#39;ll be skipping all the drama and just get to the point.  I won&#38;#39;t add
unnecessary info that doesn&#38;#39;t really matter, though people would usually tell
you all about it.  lol&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;hr&#62;
&#60;p&#62;This was written the 15.01.2014 at 11:40.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;All right so first of all the packing.  It wasn&#38;#39;t all that special TBH.  Well
mine wasn&#38;#39;t, my family&#38;#39;s was.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I took two shirts, 1 polo, 2 jeans, like 9 pair of socks and less than 8 pairs
of underwear.  Plus some stuff for the cold.  That&#38;#39;s all.  I&#38;#39;m not really sure
about the rest of my family.  lol&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;So we left at around 12:30 from Taxco de Alarcon (IIRC) on a bus to Cuernavaca,
once that got there we got in a Taxi and went to another bus terminal where we
would get a bus that goes directly to the airport.  So we did.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;So we got to the airport and we just checked-in, no troubles, we ate some and
then we just waited to board the plane.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I&#38;#39;d like to point out at this point there was like a 50 person line to get on
the plane.  We were able to skip that thanks to my magic of my seat being moved
and letting me and my family just skip the whole line.  Yay for magic!&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;We flew with Lufthansa airlines. It was a really nice service, the staff was
very nice and knew very good English.  Also everybody was good looking (but
that&#38;#39;s to be expected from an airline, AFAIK).&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;We arrived ahead of schedule, I&#38;#39;m told, but we left behind schedule, I&#38;#39;m told.
So I guess I&#38;#39;m just really good at planes.  lol&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Then we took another air plane but this one was just a 45 minute flight or so.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Next step was to take a bus to the train station and ride the train to the
Grenchen Nord station.  So we missed our stop, not really but we didn&#38;#39;t know
that the doors had to be opened manually (by pressing a button) so we missed the
stop.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;We contacted our friends over here and they told us to just take the train to
the Grenchen Süd station, which was actually nearer to our destination (but
required a train switch).&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;So we rode the train to Grenchen Süd, this time we knew how to open the door,
got off and familiar faces were there so all is well.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Got a car ride to the place we&#38;#39;re staying at, unpacked a bit, took a shower and
went to sleep.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;And we&#38;#39;re back to the present time of me writing this. I actually just woke up
and I have no internet, everybody else just started waking up.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;OK so now to the all important lessons (that I can remember) learned of every
trip:&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;ul&#62;
&#60;li&#62;For god&#38;#39;s sake keep calm! It is not nice to be nervous or to be around someone
that&#38;#39;s nervous.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;Travelling on air planes isn&#38;#39;t as special as it used to be.  Now there&#38;#39;s
screens on the seats and all kinds of stuff to cheat with getting
entertainment.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;Buses and trains require you to open the door, they will &#60;em&#62;not&#60;/em&#62; open alone at
every stop.  Know where you&#38;#39;re going and at which stop it is you&#38;#39;re getting
off.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;If on a new area, keep track of what people are doing, it will help you figure
out what to do yourself.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;/ul&#62;
&#60;p&#62;And those are all I can think of. This was written in one go so it should be
fairly consistent.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;If you find any typo (especially with names) please &#60;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Greduan/eduantech.docpad/blob/master/src/render/posts/my-trip-to-switzerland-part-1.html.md&#34;&#62;make a pull
request&#60;/a&#62;
fixing it and I will happily merge. :)&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Thank you for reading! You can share your thoughts with me through email at
&#60;a href=&#34;&#38;#x6d;&#38;#x61;&#38;#105;&#38;#108;&#38;#x74;&#38;#x6f;&#38;#58;&#38;#101;&#38;#100;&#38;#117;&#38;#97;&#38;#110;&#38;#108;&#38;#97;&#38;#118;&#38;#97;&#38;#113;&#38;#117;&#38;#101;&#38;#x40;&#38;#103;&#38;#x6d;&#38;#97;&#38;#x69;&#38;#x6c;&#38;#x2e;&#38;#99;&#38;#111;&#38;#x6d;&#34;&#62;&#38;#101;&#38;#100;&#38;#117;&#38;#97;&#38;#110;&#38;#108;&#38;#97;&#38;#118;&#38;#97;&#38;#113;&#38;#117;&#38;#101;&#38;#x40;&#38;#103;&#38;#x6d;&#38;#97;&#38;#x69;&#38;#x6c;&#38;#x2e;&#38;#99;&#38;#111;&#38;#x6d;&#60;/a&#62;. :)&#60;/p&#62;
<hr/><p>The post <a href="http://greduan.github.io/posts/my-trip-to-switzerland-part-1.html">My Trip to Switzerland, Part 1, Getting There</a> appeard first on <a href="http://greduan.github.io">EduanTech</a>.</p></content>
		</entry>
			<entry>
			<title>A Love Letter to Arch Linux</title>
			<link href="http://greduan.github.io/posts/a-love-letter-to-arch-linux.html"/>
			<updated>2013-12-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
			<id>http://greduan.github.io/posts/a-love-letter-to-arch-linux.html</id>
			<content type="html">&#60;p&#62;This is a love letter to Arch Linux. It&#38;#39;s the first time I write something like this, it was very fun. If you see anything in between square brackets (&#60;code&#62;[]&#60;/code&#62;) it&#38;#39;s an author&#38;#39;s note. Note that some stuff is exaggerated for the drama but my feelings are still true.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;hr&#62;

&#60;p&#62;Arch, I remember it clear as day how I abandoned you in July for a Mac Mini. I remember typing the last &#60;code&#62;sudo systemctl poweroff&#60;/code&#62; you would see for over 3 months. I remember the slowness with which you turned off that last time.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I remember the speed and enthusiasm with which you booted up after months of hanging around the modem in storage, only to see your sadness when I turned you off quickly as I was going to install Windows 7 over you. [Was going to lend computer.]&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I remember downloading your torrent again a week ago, I remember the speed with which you downloaded and with which you &#60;code&#62;dd&#60;/code&#62;&#38;#39;d to an 8GB USB.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;It is completely understandeable that you had a tantrum when I came back to you, it is completely understandeable that you gave me a hard time with the internet.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;And of course, the modem, it is completely understandeable that you have trouble with him, it is completely understandeable that the modem rejects a second connection without being reset after you left him as soon as I tried to install you again. [This is a reference to the fact my damn modem has to be restarted every time this computer wants to connect to it.]&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;YET! After convincing your sister to help me (ArchBang) you were willing to work again for me. And now every time I boot up you&#38;#39;re there to welcome me home.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I will always love you, Arch. I promise I won&#38;#39;t be promiscuous again. I promise I won&#38;#39;t leave you again for another OS. I promise I will look after you, even when I get new computers. You&#38;#39;re the only one for me.&#60;/p&#62;
<hr/><p>The post <a href="http://greduan.github.io/posts/a-love-letter-to-arch-linux.html">A Love Letter to Arch Linux</a> appeard first on <a href="http://greduan.github.io">EduanTech</a>.</p></content>
		</entry>
			<entry>
			<title>Switching From zsh to fish</title>
			<link href="http://greduan.github.io/posts/switching-from-zsh-to-fish.html"/>
			<updated>2013-11-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
			<id>http://greduan.github.io/posts/switching-from-zsh-to-fish.html</id>
			<content type="html">&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;Note that I already switched back to zsh. lol&#60;/em&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;In this post I&#38;#39;ll be talking about my experience with switching from zsh (&#60;strong&#62;Z&#60;/strong&#62; &#60;strong&#62;sh&#60;/strong&#62;ell) to fish (&#60;strong&#62;F&#60;/strong&#62;riendly &#60;strong&#62;I&#60;/strong&#62;nteractive &#60;strong&#62;sh&#60;/strong&#62;ell). I&#38;#39;m not gonna talk about how or why it&#38;#39;s better than the other shells, I&#38;#39;m only gonna talk about the process of switching.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Where to start... well, how about starting with the fact that I tried to do the switch before? I did try to do the switch before, I don&#38;#39;t remember exactly what problems I had last time but I&#38;#39;m pretty sure it was something with Vim or something.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I decided to try the switch again taking advantage of the fact that a new version had been released recently (&#60;a href=&#34;http://fishshell.com/release_notes.html&#34;&#62;v2.1.0&#60;/a&#62;). Seemed like a good idea to try again, also the fact that I like the features it has, of course.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;The switch wasn&#38;#39;t as problem-free as I wished but it was quite a smooth process.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;First, I was running across problems with Vim which I imagine I wasn&#38;#39;t able to solve last time, but I solved this time. The problem was a startup error that Vim was complaining about not finding a certain file or something. I just had to add the following to the top of my &#60;code&#62;.vimrc&#60;/code&#62; file to fix it:&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;pre class=&#34;highlight&#34;&#62;&#60;code class=&#34;hljs no-highlight&#34;&#62;if $SHELL =~ &#38;#39;fish&#38;#39;
    set shell=/bin/sh
endif
&#60;/code&#62;&#60;/pre&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Basically, if Vim can detect the &#60;code&#62;$SHELL&#60;/code&#62; variable is &#60;code&#62;fish&#60;/code&#62; it&#38;#39;ll tell Vim to interact with the current shell as if it was &#60;code&#62;sh&#60;/code&#62;. As I understand it, don&#38;#39;t take my word for it, please. That fixed that.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Another problem I was running into was that Emacs was complaining about not being able to find the &#60;code&#62;package.el&#60;/code&#62; file. The reason for the error was that I was opening an old version of Emacs (v22.x). This was just a matter of updating the &#60;code&#62;$PATH&#60;/code&#62; variable, that was done with the following line of code in my &#60;code&#62;config.fish&#60;/code&#62; file:&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;pre class=&#34;highlight&#34;&#62;&#60;code class=&#34;hljs no-highlight&#34;&#62;set PATH /usr/local/bin /usr/local/sbin /usr/local/share/npm/bin /usr/local/opt/ruby/bin $HOME/bin $HOME/.tmuxifier/tmuxifier/bin $PATH
&#60;/code&#62;&#60;/pre&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Umm... Those were the only real note-worthy parts. The rest were just a matter of translating zsh to fish. You can find the latest version of my config files here: &#60;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Greduan/dotfiles/tree/master/config/fish&#34;&#62;https://github.com/Greduan/dotfiles/tree/master/config/fish&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;If there&#38;#39;s something you think could be said better or is plain wrong in this post feel free to &#60;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Greduan/eduantech.docpad/blob/master/src/render/posts/switching-from-zsh-to-fish.html.md&#34;&#62;modify it&#60;/a&#62; and make a pull request for it!&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Thank you for reading! You can share your thoughts with me through email at &#60;a href=&#34;&#38;#x6d;&#38;#x61;&#38;#x69;&#38;#108;&#38;#x74;&#38;#x6f;&#38;#58;&#38;#x65;&#38;#100;&#38;#117;&#38;#x61;&#38;#x6e;&#38;#x6c;&#38;#x61;&#38;#118;&#38;#97;&#38;#x71;&#38;#x75;&#38;#x65;&#38;#64;&#38;#x67;&#38;#109;&#38;#x61;&#38;#x69;&#38;#108;&#38;#46;&#38;#x63;&#38;#x6f;&#38;#109;&#34;&#62;&#38;#x65;&#38;#100;&#38;#117;&#38;#x61;&#38;#x6e;&#38;#x6c;&#38;#x61;&#38;#118;&#38;#97;&#38;#x71;&#38;#x75;&#38;#x65;&#38;#64;&#38;#x67;&#38;#109;&#38;#x61;&#38;#x69;&#38;#108;&#38;#46;&#38;#x63;&#38;#x6f;&#38;#109;&#60;/a&#62;. :)&#60;/p&#62;
<hr/><p>The post <a href="http://greduan.github.io/posts/switching-from-zsh-to-fish.html">Switching From zsh to fish</a> appeard first on <a href="http://greduan.github.io">EduanTech</a>.</p></content>
		</entry>
			<entry>
			<title>Light Table, The New Emacs</title>
			<link href="http://greduan.github.io/posts/light-table-the-new-emacs.html"/>
			<updated>2013-11-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
			<id>http://greduan.github.io/posts/light-table-the-new-emacs.html</id>
			<content type="html">&#60;p&#62;The title may be misleading so I&#38;#39;m gonna make it clear right now. I couldn&#38;#39;t come up with anything better. It&#38;#39;s gonna stay like that, so you can make suggestions for a better title but I won&#38;#39;t change the title.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;So let me explain why I chose this title. That&#38;#39;s what this post is about.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;There is a popular saying that Vim users love to use against Emacs users in the holy editor wars. That saying is &#38;quot;Emacs would make a great OS, if only it had a good text editor.&#38;quot; or something along those lines.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;And I can sort of agree with that. Emacs&#38;#39; editor is not superior to Vim&#38;#39;s in almost any front. But let&#38;#39;s look at the bright side of that saying.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;They&#38;#39;re criticizing the text editor. But they&#38;#39;re acknowledging it as an OS. In other words it apparently can be extended immensely. And it has proven to be able to do just that. It has just about anything that can be done in text. Email reader, news reader, chat, calendar, you name it. And if it isn&#38;#39;t already implemented, you can do it yourself! ;)&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;And of course, it can be extended immensely towards developing. Debuggers, the CLI, automatic compiling functionality, people have made it an IDE as well. So its limits are practically none. Oh and let&#38;#39;s not forget about the language you use to customize it. Emacs Lisp, A.K.A. Elisp; Its own dialect of Lisp. You can&#38;#39;t get a lot more customizable than that.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Except you can... Enter Light Table!&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;http://www.lighttable.com/&#34;&#62;Light Table&#60;/a&#62; is one of the new kids on the block. It is coded in &#60;a href=&#34;http://clojure.org/clojurescript&#34;&#62;ClojureScript&#60;/a&#62;, a Lisp dialect that essentially compiles to JS. The other new kid is &#60;a href=&#34;https://github.com/limetext/lime&#34;&#62;Lime&#60;/a&#62;, but he still hasn&#38;#39;t got a working frontend (at the time of writing).&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;http://www.chris-granger.com/&#34;&#62;Chris Granger&#60;/a&#62; (the main dev of Light Table) has created a unique architecture with Light Table. (As I understand it) you can add or remove anything and everything. Well maybe not everything since you&#38;#39;ll always want some stuff there but you know what I mean. Think about the ECS (&#60;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Entity_component_system&#34;&#62;Entity Component System&#60;/a&#62;), that&#38;#39;s almost &#60;em&#62;exactly&#60;/em&#62; what Light Table has as an architecture. It is the first text editor of its kind in this sense.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;He has created a very interesting system with Light Table where the basic text editor is loaded by default. All of the text editor you get by default are just behaviours. These behaviours can be added, removed, disabled, enabled. I&#38;#39;m sure you get where I&#38;#39;m going with this.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;It could be anything and everything with due time! It could be the first real competitor for Emacs as well in terms of customizability. Think about it, it&#38;#39;s written in ClojureScript, a Lisp dialect, you can add or remove behaviours, to the point where you can make it a NotePad or a browser if you liked.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;One thing to note is that it is using &#60;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rogerwang/node-webkit&#34;&#62;node-webkit&#60;/a&#62; as it&#38;#39;s platform. It allows you to call Node.js from the DOM. That&#38;#39;s right, Light Table the text editor with almost no limits is technically a web browser.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;That means JS is its limit. If you can&#38;#39;t do it with JS (and &#60;a href=&#34;http://nodejs.org/&#34;&#62;Node.js&#60;/a&#62;) you can&#38;#39;t do it in Light Table. But if you can do it in JS you can do it in Light Table. JS is quickly becoming the one language to write. JS is found almost everywhere nowadays. So I think Chris has made a smart decision when he decided to write it in ClojureScript.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;The main point is, it&#38;#39;s got (almost) no limit on what can be added &#60;em&#62;and&#60;/em&#62; no limit on what can be removed, something Emacs is missing.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Oh and one more thing. Emacs is millions of lines of Elisp plus the C code it uses. Light Table is only around twelve thousand lines of ClojureScript, at the time of writing (v0.5.18).&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;So yeah. My point is, it&#38;#39;ll possibly be &#60;em&#62;the&#60;/em&#62; text editor once a couple of years pass after it&#38;#39;s full release and it is more mature.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;If there&#38;#39;s something you think could be said better in this post feel free to &#60;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Greduan/eduantech.docpad/blob/master/src/render/posts/light-table-the-new-emacs.html.md&#34;&#62;modify it&#60;/a&#62; and make a pull request for it!&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Thank you for reading! You can share your thoughts with me through email at &#60;a href=&#34;&#38;#x6d;&#38;#x61;&#38;#x69;&#38;#x6c;&#38;#x74;&#38;#x6f;&#38;#x3a;&#38;#x65;&#38;#100;&#38;#x75;&#38;#x61;&#38;#110;&#38;#x6c;&#38;#97;&#38;#118;&#38;#x61;&#38;#113;&#38;#x75;&#38;#101;&#38;#64;&#38;#103;&#38;#109;&#38;#97;&#38;#x69;&#38;#x6c;&#38;#46;&#38;#99;&#38;#x6f;&#38;#x6d;&#34;&#62;&#38;#x65;&#38;#100;&#38;#x75;&#38;#x61;&#38;#110;&#38;#x6c;&#38;#97;&#38;#118;&#38;#x61;&#38;#113;&#38;#x75;&#38;#101;&#38;#64;&#38;#103;&#38;#109;&#38;#97;&#38;#x69;&#38;#x6c;&#38;#46;&#38;#99;&#38;#x6f;&#38;#x6d;&#60;/a&#62;. :)&#60;/p&#62;
<hr/><p>The post <a href="http://greduan.github.io/posts/light-table-the-new-emacs.html">Light Table, The New Emacs</a> appeard first on <a href="http://greduan.github.io">EduanTech</a>.</p></content>
		</entry>
			<entry>
			<title>Open Source Games Without Going Poor</title>
			<link href="http://greduan.github.io/posts/open-source-games-without-going-poor.html"/>
			<updated>2013-10-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
			<id>http://greduan.github.io/posts/open-source-games-without-going-poor.html</id>
			<content type="html">&#60;p&#62;&#60;strong&#62;TL;DR: Release your game for a fee, after a certain amount of time release source code, continue selling pre-compiled version to public. Open source games.&#60;/strong&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;So what&#38;#39;s the idea? What do I mean with open source games?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I love open source. I try to make everything I use open source whenever possible. There are lot of great projects I use and sometimes contribute to that are open source. For example Clojure, Vim, Chromium (all of which I use) or DocPad (to which I contribute).&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I also love games, I mean who doesn&#38;#39;t? Doesn&#38;#39;t have to be video games for it to be a game, there&#38;#39;s also physical games like Tag, Hide-and-Seek etc. They are all free, open source, they&#38;#39;re just an idea, you see kids modifying games in order to make them more interesting all the time! Most video games aren&#38;#39;t open source however. You pay for a game, you play it, finish it (or complete it), move on to the next game. The games that &#60;em&#62;are&#60;/em&#62; open source are so simple there isn&#38;#39;t any gain in making them not open source, if anything you lose from making them closed source.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;A lot of, if not all developers love open source. However, a lot of us developers make games for a living. We can&#38;#39;t make them open source, we would have to live off of donations, which are inconsistent if there are donations and if there aren&#38;#39;t well... we&#38;#39;re in deep shit if we don&#38;#39;t have a job.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Now, this is an idea I had that tries to solve that. Us open source lovers who want to make a decent living off of making &#60;em&#62;open source&#60;/em&#62; games will be able to do this with this idea I had.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;The idea is simple, release the game to the public for a fee as usual, however after an agreed amount of time, which you decide, release the game&#38;#39;s source. Make it open source. However, continue selling the pre-compiled game to the public.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;So it&#38;#39;s really a simple idea. You release the game for a fee for a certain amount of time in order to make a living or at least make up for what you lost in the development process. After that certain amount of time is up you release the source.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;This makes the game open source however you are still making an income from non-techie users or just nice users.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;So why would this work? Smart users would just wait a year or whatever and compile the source and done, they won&#38;#39;t pay anything, why would they? They&#38;#39;re &#60;em&#62;smart&#60;/em&#62; about it. This idea is just a recipe for disaster!&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Well, the way I see it, if your game is good enough, people won&#38;#39;t care about paying for it. They won&#38;#39;t mind keeping you alive by giving you $5 or whatever your game costs. In fact they would be glad that you made that game. AND, as an added bonus, if they&#38;#39;re interested in the game&#38;#39;s source code to see how you figured out this holy-crap-that-looks-crazy thing in your game, they can do that.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Most probably if the don&#38;#39;t pay for your game it&#38;#39;s because they want some sort of trial period or they can&#38;#39;t even afford the game anyway. So really you&#38;#39;re not losing much.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Of course, there&#38;#39;ll be the users that just compile the game, play it, finish and complete it and uninstall it, never touching it again. How many users are like that? In my experience with people, not many.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;So this is a trust issue. Do you trust your users enough to be nice enough to let you live? Or not? I trust them, they&#38;#39;re playing my awesome game, why wouldn&#38;#39;t they want to keep me alive for me to make more games?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;You can look at it the other way, maybe people are interested in your game not for the game itself, but the code. They approach your game&#38;#39;s code because you figured something out that they&#38;#39;ve had a hard time figuring out. They figure out stuff for you that you did wrong and make pull requests.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;So you have an income one way or another. Be it through code or money. If they help with the code they help with the overall game so the sales would be better, for example.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;This is just a crazy but not impossible idea I had while thinking on my bed, so it&#38;#39;s not really fleshed out, since there isn&#38;#39;t anything to flesh out.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Also it&#38;#39;s kinda hastily written, so if there&#38;#39;s something you think could be said better in this post feel free to &#60;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Greduan/eduantech.docpad/blob/master/src/render/posts/open-source-games-without-going-poor.html.md&#34;&#62;modify it&#60;/a&#62; and make a pull request for it!&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Here is some further reading you might be interested in:&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;ul&#62;
&#60;li&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;http://raamdev.com/income-ethics-series/&#34;&#62;Income Ethics - Raam Dev&#60;/a&#62; - A very deep look into a similar subject, he mentions something extremly similar to this idea in &#60;a href=&#34;http://raamdev.com/income-ethics-series/#public_domain&#34;&#62;this section&#60;/a&#62; of his post.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;/ul&#62;
<hr/><p>The post <a href="http://greduan.github.io/posts/open-source-games-without-going-poor.html">Open Source Games Without Going Poor</a> appeard first on <a href="http://greduan.github.io">EduanTech</a>.</p></content>
		</entry>
			<entry>
			<title>The Switch to DocPad</title>
			<link href="http://greduan.github.io/posts/the-switch-to-docpad.html"/>
			<updated>2013-06-16T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
			<id>http://greduan.github.io/posts/the-switch-to-docpad.html</id>
			<content type="html">&#60;p&#62;Well I finally switched to something else than WordPress.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I switched to &#60;a href=&#34;http://docpad.org&#34;&#62;DocPad&#60;/a&#62;, the &#60;a href=&#34;http://nodejs.org/&#34;&#62;Node.js&#60;/a&#62; based static website generator. It&#38;#39;s a static website generator but if you wish it can be completely dynamic.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I am using Markdown to write my posts. Using &#60;a href=&#34;http://coffeekup.org/&#34;&#62;CoffeeKup&#60;/a&#62; and &#60;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sstephenson/eco&#34;&#62;Eco&#60;/a&#62; as templating languages and normal JavaScript for the &#60;code&#62;.js&#60;/code&#62; files. And I am using &#60;a href=&#34;http://sass-lang.com/&#34;&#62;SCSS&#60;/a&#62; for the CSS, of course.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Also, now my website is being hosted by GitHub Pages, so that&#38;#39;s cool.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;That is all. Hope you like the changes. :)&#60;/p&#62;
<hr/><p>The post <a href="http://greduan.github.io/posts/the-switch-to-docpad.html">The Switch to DocPad</a> appeard first on <a href="http://greduan.github.io">EduanTech</a>.</p></content>
		</entry>
	</feed>
